As you watch this video, you will
discover how the course is structured.
The course consists of seven thematic modules.
Each module offers a set of
video lectures with reviews,
recommendations, examples and tips.
Each module also contains
additional information,
useful links and tests
that will help you
monitor your progress
and understanding.
The seven thematic modules are:
Module 1. Introduction - you are
now listening to this module.
The following modules will be
presented by colleagues in the field.
Module 2. Publications
Module 3. Scientometrics and
Bibliography
Module 4. Personal Effectiveness
Module 5. Self-presentation
Module 6. Commercialization of
research results
Module 7. Tools
You may also be interested
in the course
evaluation rubric.
Your mark is made up of two parts:
1) Successful completion of tests
at the end of
each module and at
the end of the course.
2) Submission of final paper.
In this section, I will elaborate
on the types of final papers that
can be submitted.
The final paper depends on
the chosen career path
in science.
There are three available
career paths.
Career Path 1
The Researcher.
As part of this path,
the main task is to research
and present the results
of your work in a
scientific conference or publish
in a scientific journal.
Choosing this path, your
final assignment
will be to write a
scientific article (that includes
a rationale aimed
towards the journal you want to submit
this article for consideration).
Career Path 2
The Popularizer.
Here the main task is to
report on the results
of your work to a
specific audience in
an accessible and
fascinating way.
You will have to present yourself as
a competent researcher and effectively
convey the essence of your work.
The final assignment
will require a short video
with a narrative detailing the reasons
for your chosen scientific field
and the importance of
your research in the field.
Career Path 3
The Entrepreneur.
The main task is to understand
the applied significance of
the results of a scientific
research and present it
as a commercial project.
In this final assignment
you will write a grant application,
containing a justification
plan to commercialize
your development.
By choosing a career path
you are also choosing
the format of your final assignment.
Your final assignment will be
peer reviewed by your fellow
classmates and teacher.
Detailed requirements and assessment
criteria for the types of final papers
can be found in the corresponding
section of the course.
Please note that all seven thematic
modules must be completed,
regardless of the type of final
paper chosen. For each
career path,
there is a key module that will
help you complete the final assignment.
It is advised
to pay extra attention
during these modules.
For example, if you choose
a researcher's path,
then it is advised to look
over the publication module.
If you choose the popularizer’s path,
it is advised to spend more time
on the self-presentation module.
And if you choose the entrepreneur’s path,
it is advised to revisit
the commercialization module.
Please feel free to ask
questions on the course forum.
It is encouraged to discuss materials
with fellow students.
As communication and the ability
to learn from each other are the keys
to success in this course
and in the field of science.
It is my pleasure to welcome
you to this course, once again.
I hope each of you discover your
own path in the field of science!
Good luck!